bookchums.com 2018-12-26

# Privacy and Policy of BookChums

### Privacy Policy

#### Scope:

This policy describes the ways we collect, store, use and protect your personal information (“Privacy Policy ” or “Policy”). This Privacy Policy describes the information, as part of the normal operation of our services, that we collect from you and what may happen to that information. Although this Policy may seem long, we have prepared it because we believe you should know as much as possible about our practices so that you can make informed decisions. Our parent, subsidiaries, and joint ventures operate under similar privacy practices as described in this Privacy Policy and, subject to the requirements of applicable law, we strive to provide a consistent set of privacy practices. 

#### Our Commitment:

At Bookchums, we are extremely proud of our commitment to protect your privacy. We value your trust in us. We will work hard to earn your confidence so that you can enthusiastically use our services and recommend us to friends and family. Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of our website (the “Site”). 

#### Your Consent:

By using the Site and/or signing up for our relevant services, you accepted this Policy and consented to the collection, storage and use of the information that you disclose, and any information that can be collected based you're your visitation and activity on such Site.

#### Notice:

By using the Site and/or signing up for our relevant services, you accepted this Policy and consented to the collection, storage and use of the information that you disclose, and any information that can be collected based you're your visitation and activity on such Site.

#### Privacy Guarantee:

We do not rent, sell, or share personal information about you with other people or nonaffiliated companies except to provide products or services you've requested, when we have your express permission, or under the following circumstances set forth herein. We may share our data, including personal information about you, with our parent, affiliates, subsidiaries, and joint ventures that are committed to serving your online needs and related services. To the extent that these entities have access to your information, they will treat it at least as protectively as they treat information they obtain from their other users. Our parent, affiliates, subsidiaries, and joint ventures follow privacy practices no less protective of all users than our practices described in this Policy, to the extent allowed by applicable law. We may also share your personal information when: 

  1. We provide the information to trusted partners who work on behalf of or with Bookchums. Although we make good faith efforts to store the information in a secure operating environment that is not available to the public, we cannot guarantee complete security.  
These companies may use your personal information to help Bookchums communicate with you about various goods and services, discounts, and other opportunities in which we think you may be interested provided by our partners. However, these companies do not have any independent right to share this information. 

  2. We will not share information unless the information relates to that of an adult or unless we obtain a parent's permission if the user is a child under age 18.

  3. We respond to warrants, court orders, or legal processes, or we need to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.

  4. We believe it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, or as otherwise required by law.

  5. Bookchums, its parent, affiliates, subsidiaries, its joint ventures, or any combination of such, will share or transfer some or all of your personal information with another business entity should we plan to, merge with, or be acquired by that business entity. Should such a combination occur, we will require that the new combined entity follow this Privacy Policy with respect to your personal information.

Please note that these third parties may be in other countries where the laws on processing personal information may be less stringent than in your country.

We cannot guarantee any information if the hardware/software you use to access our Site has any kind of hacking, phishing, keystroke logging and/or other key-logging software/hardware, or the like enabled/installed on such software/hardware which you use to access the Site.

You may choose to give us personal information, such as your name and address or e-mail ID that may be needed, for example, to correspond with you, to download our white papers or to provide you with a subscription. If you tell us that you do not want us to use this information as a basis for further contact with you and/or you do not want us to share your information, we will respect your wishes. We will make a sincere effort to respond in a timely manner to your requests to correct inaccuracies in your personal information. To correct inaccuracies in your personal information please return the message containing the inaccuracies to the sender with details of the correction requested.

#### Archiving and Display of Website Contents:

Search engines and other sites not affiliated with Bookchums may archive or otherwise make available various screen shots, search terms, web postings, conversations, as well as other information. Bookchums has no control over how such information and/or content is used.

#### How We Use Cookies:

When you visit the Site, we collect your IP address and standard web log information, such as your browser type and the pages you accessed on our Site. Our servers automatically record information ("Log Data") created by your use of the Services. Log Data may include information such as your IP address, browser type, the referring domain, pages visited, and search terms. Other actions, such as interactions with advertisements, may also be included in Log Data.

We sometimes collect anonymous information from visits to our Sites to help us provide better customer service. When you access our website, we, or companies we hire to track how our Site is used, may place small data files called "cookies" on your computer. We send a "session cookie" to your computer when you log into your account. This type of cookie helps us to recognize you if you visit multiple pages on our Site during the same session, so that we don't need to ask you for your password on each page. Once you log out or close your browser, this cookie expires, and no longer has any effect. We also may use longer-lasting cookies for other purposes such as to display your e-mail address on our sign-in form, so that you don't need to retype the e-mail address each time you log in to your account. We may use this data to analyze trends and statistics and to help us provide better customer service. We maintain the highest levels of confidentiality for this information, our affiliates and vendors, if any, follow the same high levels of confidentiality. Anonymous information is used and analyzed only at an aggregate level to help us understand trends and patterns. None of this information is reviewed at an individual level. If you do not want your transaction details used in this manner, you can either disable your cookies or opt-out at the download or request page. You are free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, but doing so may interfere with your use of our website.

#### How We Protect, Store, and Use Personal Information We Collect:

Throughout this Policy, we use the term "personal information" to describe information that can be associated with a specific person and can be used to identify that person. We do not consider personal information to include information that has been anonymized so that it does not identify a specific user.

We store and process your personal information on our computers in the United States and at various customer and operations support centers, and we protect it by maintaining physical, electronic and procedural safeguards. We use computer safeguards such as firewalls and data encryption; we enforce physical access controls to our buildings and files. We authorize access to personal information only for those employees who require it to fulfill their job responsibilities.

Our primary purpose in collecting personal information is to provide you with a safe, smooth, efficient, and customized experience. To that end, we use your personal information to: 

  * Provide the services and customer support you request.
  * Process transactions and send notices about your transactions.
  * Resolve disputes, collect fees, and troubleshoot problems.
  * Prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities, and enforce our [Terms of Use.](http://www.bookchums.com/termsofuse.php)
  * Customize, measure, and improve our services and the content and layout of our Site.
  * Send you targeted marketing, service update notices, and promotional offers based on your communication preferences.

#### Collection of Information for Financial Transactions:

If you open an account involving financial transactions, we or other third parties with whom we have contracted for collection of information may ask you to submit the following types of information from you:

  * Provide the services and customer support you request.
  * Process transactions and send notices about your transactions.

Before permitting you to use our service, we may require you to provide additional information that we can use to verify your identity or address or manage risk, such as your date of birth, national ID number, Nationality, and other identifying information. We may also obtain information about you from third parties such as credit bureaus and identity verification services.

When you are using our service, we collect information about your account transactions, and we may collect information about your computer or other access device for fraud prevention purposes.

Regardless, we will not disclose your credit card number and/or bank account number to anyone you have paid or who has paid you through our Site, except with your express permission or if we are required to do so to comply with a valid regulatory or law enforcement request, to cooperate in an ongoing law enforcement investigation, or as otherwise required by law.

Finally, we may collect additional information from or about you in other ways not specifically described here. For example, we may collect information related to your contact with our customer support team or store results when you respond to a survey. 

#### How to Control Communications with Us:

Bookchums may, if you so elect, send direct mailers to you at the address, email address, or at other contact information given to us by you. You can control how we use your contact information to market our services to you by changing your preferences; you also have the option of “opting-out” or “unsubscribing” to any or all direct mailings by way of links provided at the bottom of each mailer. We respect your privacy and in the event that you choose to not receive such mailers, we will take all steps to remove you from the list.

#### How to Access Personal Information:

You can review and edit your personal information at any time by logging in to your account and clicking the “My Account” tab on your “Dashboard”.

#### Our Policy towards Children:

If you become aware that your child has provided us with personal information without your consent, please contact us at[ admin@bookchums.com. ](mailto:admin@bookchums.com)We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 18, without parental consent. If we become aware that a child under 18 years has provided us with personal information, we take steps to remove such information and terminate the child's account.

#### Applicable Law and Dispute Resolution:

By visiting this Site you hereby accept that this Policy shall be governed by the local laws of Pune, Maharashtra, INDIA, without regard to its conflict of laws provisions and by visiting this Site you hereby accept that the jurisdiction for any and all dispute(s) arising out of or in connection with the present Policy shall be litigated and/or settled in the local courts in Pune, Maharashtra, INDIA only.
